

# **PROFILE**

A Reliable Quality Assurance test engineer with over 2+ years of experience working in a company to ensure the highest software quality and bringing forth a seasoned history of helping a project achieve success and improve efficiency.

# CONTACT

PHONE:

+91 7358512884

LINKEDIN:

Haryish Elangumaran | LinkedIn

GITHUB:

https://github.com/Haryish

EMAIL:

haryishkumaran 16@gmail.com

## **ADDRESS**

39/44, Pillaiyar Koil Street, Tondiarpet, Chennai, Tamilnadu, India. Pin code: 600081

# TECHNICAL SKILLS

MS word, MS Excel, Jira, Confluence, Git and GitHub, Front End (Software Engineering): {HTML, CSS, ReactJS}

## **LANGUAGE**

Tamil (native) English - Proficient Hindi – Intermediate

# HARYISH ELANGUMARAN

Quality Assurance Test Engineer

## **EDUCATION**

### Anna University (Center of Distance education)

September 2022 - Present
Currently Pursuing Master of Computer Application (MCA)

## Dwaraka Doss Govardhan Doss Vaishnav College

June 2018 - June 2021

Graduated as Bachelor of Computer Applications (BCA) with 80.3 %

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

#### **Cognizant Technology Solution**

## - Programmer Analyst (March 2024–Present)

- Utilized various testing techniques to identify defects and ensure quality
- Developed and maintained test environments that accurately replicated production and enabled stable testing
- Developed and maintained a database of test cases in Jira (X-Ray) for use in future projects

## - Programmer (October 2022–March 2024)

- Developed an end-to-end testing procedure that ensured the system behaved as expected
- Performed functional and regression testing to ensure the software meets user requirements
- Developed test scenarios, test cases, and traceability reports to ensure the highest level of software quality coverage.

### - Programmer Trainee (October 2021–October 2022)

- I was trained in Quality Assurance and Engineering (Manual + Automation with Selenium) through which I learnt functional testing, Agile Methodologies, SQL, and Frontend testing through Selenium with Java.
- Aligned with a project in the Banking and Financial Industry, in which practiced working on Manual Testing by involving activities underlying STLC phases such as Test Design documents and artefacts (test cases, test scenario preparation), test data preparation and environment verification. Undergone through the process of credit card functionalities to execute test cases Manually.

## **SELF PASED PROJECT**

#### **Test Evidence Validator**

October 2022 - November 2022

- > The tool created under front end to validate the load number and time difference between each screen prints pasted in test evidence document that are taken during manual test execution.
- Collaborated with the team of 4 members to build this tool with the Frontend technologies like HTML, CSS, JS, Bootstrap and for Backend we use Django framework and Tesseract Library from Python for Image processing and scanning.

## PROJECT UNDER BUSINESS UNIT

#### NewDay Cards PVT. LTD.,

February 2022 - Present

- Roles and Responsibilities:
  - Develop comprehensive test plans, RTM, Test scenarios and test cases based on project requirements and specifications.
  - Execute test cases, both manually and using automated testing tools, to identify software defects and inconsistencies.
  - Document and track defects, using a bug tracking system, and provide detailed information to developers for resolution.
  - o Conduct regression testing to verify bug fixes and ensure the overall stability of the software.
- Skills gained and contributed:
  - o MS Word, MS Excel, Beginning level of Excel VBA for Macro, Rest API testing via postman, Test Management tools and add-ons (Jira, Confluence and Jira Xray)
- Additional Contributions:
  - Developed and shared the testing tool to validate the contents in consent document and email content for document related test scenarios.
  - o Retested and verified the issues on End-to-end tests

## PROFESSIONAL SKILLS AND CERTIFICATIONS:

# REST API for Beginner to Intermediate

Provider: Udemy Date: August 2023

## **SQL for Beginners using MySQL and Database Design**

Provider: Udemy Date: June 2022

#### **Git and Github**

Provider: Udemy Date: August 2023

#### Java Database Connectivity

Provider: Udemy Date: November 2021

Skills	Level	Estimate
Java	Intermediate	75%
JavaScript	Basic	40%
Python	Advanced	80%
Selenium in JavaPython	Intermediate	80%
TestNG	Intermediate	50%
Selenium in Python	Intermediate	50%
PyTest	Intermediate	50%
Rest API for testing	Intermediate	80%
Front End web development	Beginner	60%
MySQL	Advanced	90%
Manual Testing	Intermediate	50%

## **EXTERNAL ACTIVITIES**

- Participated in a hackathon contest on providing the tool at different problem statements. Through that I got chance to work and collaborate with a team on the project Test data validator
- Contributed 20+ hours in mentoring the freshers and interns of Quality Engineering and Assurance through Buddy Mentoring Program, in a span of 6 months starting from February 2023.